JHON ARIAS Software Engineer (*(window).scrolllopt/ clar? css('padding-top')

I'm a Full-stack web developer with four years of experience. I have a strong understanding of algorithms, data structures, Linux, AWS, Ruby, Object-oriented Programming, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, NodeJS, and some Front-End frameworks such as ReactJS and ElectronJS. Passionate about web development, game development, and continues-learning.



jhonarmont@hotmail.com



GITHUB.COM/JHON112



(+57) 3117110846



EDUCATION

Software engineer. Holberton School, 2020

diploma in Cybersecurity University Institute ITM, 2020

Full stack Ruby on Rails developer Make It Real bootcamp, 2018

SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails
- JavaScript (ES6)
- ReactJS & ElectronJS
- JOuery
- RSpec
- Python
- (
- Whiteboarding
- NodeJS

SPECIALIZATIONS

- Web Applications
- Full-stack Development
- Data Structures
- RESTful web services
- Databases
- User Interface Implementation

EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Work closely with the clients to ensure their requirements are clear and well documented.

 Create Jira cards with tasks according to client needs and previous discussions in stand-up meetings.
- Precisely estimate tasks/projects for clients and make sure deadlines are met according to estimations.
- Work closely with QA to ensure new features are correctly working after release.
- Manage the time to work on multiple projects at the same time while maintaining an excellent management and development process.

VERY

MAY 20201 - CURRENT

FULL-STACK RUBY-ON-RAILS DEVELOPER

- Provide Ruby-On-Rails quality code that follows the company guidelines and expectations.
- Being part of discussions that define the future of a planned project.
- Review partners' pull requests and make sure they follow good practices.
- Help in cloud infrastructure monitoring and management
- Help with code deploys to QA servers and ensure the QA process goes correctly.
- Make sure the code was correctly covered with RSpec tests.

VISTA HIGHER LEARNING

MAY 2020 -MAY 2021

RUBY ON RAILS BACK-END DEVELOPER

- Help find appropriate solutions and suggest new ways to improve the company processes.
- Add integrations third-party integrations by connecting to REST APIs
- Deliver efficient and reliable code following company standards
- Being part of project-related discussions in the different SCRUM meetings.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

- Developing front-end website architectures following a mock-up design.
- Seeing through a project from conception to the finished product and make sure all the requirements are fulfilled.
- Contribute to software architecture discussions and decisions.

AYENDA HOTELES

MEDELLIN, CO

DEC 2014 -FEB 2015

ENOVEL SOLUCIONES

MEDELLIN, CO

SEP 2018 -AUG 2019